Nathan Neumann

Nathan.J.Neumann.20@dartmouth.edu (619) 699-9903

Skills:

Programming: Proficient in Java, JavaScript, CSS, R, Python, C, HTML, and CSS. Experience in projects ranging from web UI design to back-end system and full-stack mobile app development.

Tools and Frameworks: Well-versed in Android Studio, the Adobe Creative Suite, Unity, and Unix computing. Significant experience with JavaScript frameworks and tools including React, Redux, Next.JS, and Electron.

Miscellaneous: Fluent in Japanese. Strong communication skills and great desire to learn.

Education:

Aug. 2016 - Present Dartmouth College GPA: 3.67

Computer Science and Quantitative Social Science Majors, Japanese Minor

Relevant Coursework: Software Design and Implementation, Full-Stack Web Development, Smartphone Programming, Data Visualization, Object-Oriented Programming

Experience:

Web Development Intern - Code Chrysalis (2018 - Present)

- Revitalized company website, including designing and developing new pages, translating
 the website with i18n, eliminating persistent bugs, refactoring the site to remove a
 redundant Redux implementation, and managing Google and Facebook traffic analytics
- Utilized resources like GitHub and Heroku to manage site improvement and deployment targets, and coordinate effectively with a team of engineers to review changes
- Assisted in JavaScript instruction in the company's foundational programming course

Computer Science Section Leader - Dartmouth College (2017-18)

- Managed and analyzed student code submissions for quality, effectiveness, and efficiency
- Provided additional instruction for students in introductory Computer Science courses

Dartmouth Beginner 12-Hour Hackathon (2017)

- Won 1st Place for development of an Android app for learning to read and write Japanese
- Self-taught Unity and C# to a practical level in a few hours of from-scratch development